newsinlevels.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy | English news and easy articles for students of English

### Privacy Policy

[English in Levels s.r.o.](http://www.englishinlevels.com/) is the creator and publisher of the web pages available at NewsinLevels.com, and all linked pages, features, content, or applications (collectively, the “Site”).  

### Extent of Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy covers English in Levels s.r.o.’s treatment of personal information that we collect when you are on the Site. This policy covers our treatment of any personal information that our business partners share with us.

This policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that English in Levels s.r.o. does not own or control, including but not limited to third party services you access through English in Levels s.r.o., or to individuals that we do not employ or manage. We collect the following types of information from our users:  

### Information Collected from Registered Visitors by Our Server

During the sign up we collect information necessary to provide the promised functions of News in Levels.

If you subscribe to our Daily News we will send you emails with the digest of the latest articles. Besides that we may also send Informative emails about the Site in general such as announcement of new functions or changes to the Site. If you want to unsubscribe from the Informative emails, just send an email to [info@newsinlevels.com](mailto:info@newsinlevels.com).

**We do not share your email address with any third party.**  

### Information Collected From All Visitors By Our Server

Whenever you interact with the Site, we may receive and store certain types of information. This information includes the data stored by the server in server logs, such as your IP address, cookie information, and the information you request from the server. English in Levels s.r.o. may use this information to detect problems with the server, make changes so that the site is easier to use or create statistics. English in Levels s.r.o. may use this data in aggregate form, that is, as a statistical measure, but not in a manner that would identify you personally.  

### Information Collected from All Visitors via Google Analytics

If you visit this site and you have javascript enabled, your actions are tracked by Google Analytics. These Google services collect the following types of information:

  * Type of user agent (web browser) used, software manufacture and version number.
  * Type of operating system
  * Screen colors (color processing ability of the users screen)
  * Javascript support
  * Flash version
  * Screen resolution
  * Network location and IP address Can include country, city, state, region, county, or any other geographic data.
  * Hostname
  * Bandwidth (internet connection speed)
  * Time of visit
  * Pages visited
  * Time spent on each page of the website
  * Referring site statistics
  * The website (URI) the user came through in order to arrive at this website (example: clicking on a hyperlink from Yahoo.com that took the user to this website)
  * Search engine query used (example: typing in a phrase into a search engine like Google, and clicking on a link from that search engine)

This data is primarily used to optimize our website for our visitors. It’s important to note that this data **DOES NOT** include any personalized identification information such as:

  * Names
  * Phone Numbers
  * Email Addresses
  * Mailing Addresses
  * Social Security Numbers
  * Bank Account Numbers
  * Credit Card Information

### Ads

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).  

### Cookies & 3rd Party Advertisements

Cookies are simple pieces of information that we store on your hard drive through your Web browser. These cookies do not collect personal information.

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our website. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

### LEARN 3000 WORDS with NEWS IN LEVELS

If you read and listen to two articles every day, your reading and listening skills can improve fast. You can learn quickly and after some time you will not have to translate into your own language. You will simply understand. **Why should you do this?**

When you listen to people in your native language, you do not translate. You simply understand. The same has to be in English. When you learn English, you have to learn the whole sentences in context.

Students, who translate English texts, do exercises and do tests are very good at translating, doing exercises and doing tests, but they have problems with understanding English in real life. In real life, nobody waits for your translation. People usually use simple English when they speak but they use it fast. **You have to understand with no translation to your native language.** If you translate, you cannot be part of communication because you are thinking about the language too much. These words are maybe hard to read but they are true.

You also have to hear every new word 5 to 10 times if you want to remember it. That’s why we use the same words in one level. If you read and hear the same words again and again, you will understand them and remember them. If you know words from one level, you can go to a higher level and learn new words. It is important to go step by step, and read and listen to words which are used in English often. This is what we do with our news. In our short news, we use words which are used in English often. [**Level 1**](http://www.newsinlevels.com/level/level-1/) has the 1000 most important words. [**Level 2**](http://www.newsinlevels.com/level/level-2/) has the 2000 most important words, [**Level 3**](http://www.newsinlevels.com/level/level-3/) has the 3000 most important words.

So, **if you want to understand English fast and learn fast, read two articles or more a day**. You can improve your reading and listening quickly when you read easy English news. We will help you learn English fast and understand it. When you use this website every day, you can learn 3000 words which you need for communication with anybody in English.

### How to improve your English with News in Levels: 

#### Reading

  1. Read all today’s articles and translate all words which you don’t understand.
  2. Read the articles from the day before and see if you remember all new words.

#### Listening

  1. Listen to all today’s news.
  2. Stop the video after every sentence and repeat the sentence.
  3. Repeat point 2 for the news which you listened to the day before.

#### Writing

  1. Answer the questions under today’s news and write them into the comments.
  2. Chat in our [Facebook Group](https://www.facebook.com/groups/104063393420200/) for at least 2 minutes. You can write about today’s news.
